<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-05T19:50:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Fields &amp;amp; Waves Lab</title><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><entry><title type="html">Metamaterial-based analog computing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/computational-MTM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Metamaterial-based analog computing" /><published>2017-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/computational-MTM</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/computational-MTM">&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with the Groups led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seas.upenn.edu/~engheta/)&quot;&gt;Nader Engheta&lt;/a&gt; (University of Pennsylvania) 
and &lt;a href=&quot;http://users.ece.utexas.edu/~aalu/)&quot;&gt;Andrea Alù&lt;/a&gt; (University of Texas at Austin), we
have put forward a general paradigm of “metamaterial analog computing” [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ109_Science_343_160_2014&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], 
in which properly designed metamaterial blocks may perform ubiquitous mathematical operations, 
such as spatial differentiation, integration or convolution, on the profile of the impinging light as 
it propagates through them (see the conceptual schematic in the figure top panel).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our idea is inspired by the earlier “calculating machines” in the form of mechanical, electronic, and hybrid analog computers, 
which have been designed in the past to perform prescribed mathematical computations. 
These solutions suffered from substantial limitations, including relatively large size and slow response, 
and were quickly dropped with the advances on digital computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure bottom panel illustrates a possible application of our proposed 
“computational metamaterials” as a Laplace filter for edge detection, 
an increasingly common image processing technique that helps software find faces and identify objects in pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These structures may be of subwavelength size, and several orders of magnitude smaller than conventional 
lens-based optical signal processing systems. 
 In particular, we have proposed two possible architectures: specially designed subwavelength metasurfaces that 
 operate in the spatial Fourier domain, combined with graded-index (GRIN) slabs or fibers; 
 and layered metamaterials that engineer the desired operator’s Green’s function directly in the space domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These results (included as one of the Highlights in Optics in 2014 in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.osa-opn.org/home/articles/volume_25/december_2014/extras/doing_math_with_light/&quot;&gt;“Optics &amp;amp; Photonics News”&lt;/a&gt;) may pave 
the way to a re-birth of optical analog computers, but at the nanoscale, 
entirely wave-based, integrable with nanophotonics and electronic, with potentially disruptive applications 
to several fields of science and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A particularly intriguing follow-up would be the design of metadevices capable of solving
 differential and/or integral equations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ109_Science_343_160_2014&quot;&gt;Silva, A., Monticone, F., Castaldi, G., Galdi, V., Alù, A., &amp;amp; Engheta, N. (2014). Performing mathematical operations with metamaterials. &lt;i&gt;Science&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;343&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(6167), 160–163.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ109_Science_343_160_2014-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ109_Science_343_160_2014-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ109_Science_343_160_2014-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1242818&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ109_Science_343_160_2014.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ109_Science_343_160_2014_SM.pdf&quot;&gt;Supplements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ109_Science_343_160_2014-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;We introduce the concept of metamaterial analog computing, based on suitably designed metamaterial blocks that can perform mathematical operations (such as spatial differentiation, integration, or convolution) on the profile of an impinging wave as it propagates through these blocks. Two approaches are presented to achieve such functionality: (i) subwavelength structured metascreens combined with graded-index waveguides and (ii) multilayered slabs designed to achieve a desired spatial Green’s function. Both techniques offer the possibility of miniaturized, potentially integrable, wave-based computing systems that are thinner than conventional lens-based optical signal and data processors by several orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ109_Science_343_160_2014-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ109_Science_343_160_2014,
  author = {Silva, Alexandre and Monticone, Francesco and Castaldi, Giuseppe and Galdi, Vincenzo and Al{\`u}, Andrea and Engheta, Nader},
  title = {{Performing mathematical operations with metamaterials}},
  journal = {Science},
  doi = {10.1126/science.1242818},
  year = {2014},
  volume = {343},
  number = {6167},
  pages = {160--163},
  month = jan,
  note = {/assets/papers/IJ109_Science_343_160_2014_SM.pdf}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="metamaterials" /><category term="metasurfaces" /><category term="analog computing" /><category term="image processing" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Multiphysics metamaterials</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/multiphysics-MTM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Multiphysics metamaterials" /><published>2017-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/multiphysics-MTM</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/multiphysics-MTM">&lt;p&gt;During the past few years, the &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/TO-MTM&quot;&gt;transformation-optics&lt;/a&gt; approach has been also successfully applied 
to the manipulation of a variety of other different physical quantities like acoustic and elastic waves, 
static magnetic and electric fields, and heat flux, in view of the mounting interest towards metamaterials 
beyond electromagnetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it seems suggestive to coherently exploit these various approaches to design 
multifunctional devices capable of performing multiple functions in different physical domains, 
most studies available in the literature deal with the design of a single functionality in a given physical domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.rowland.harvard.edu/people/yuki-sato&quot;&gt;Yuki Sato&lt;/a&gt;’s Group (Harvard University), 
we have recently introduced an approach to the design of metamaterial shells 
capable of governing different physicals phenomena in an independent fashion [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the mathematical viewpoint, our relies on the well-known coordinate-transformation framework. 
Viewing the rerouting of energy flow as a distortion of space from a coordinate transformation, 
this technique provides a powerful and systematic recipe for designing and fabricating artificial 
structures that can mold the flow of a given physical quantity in a desired fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventionally, this theory is applied to a single physical domain. 
In our approach, we instead exploit separate but intertwined coordinate transformations to 
simultaneously manipulate multiple physical phenomena in independent fashions. 
Thus, for instance, a material may be designed to exhibit a particular thermal functionality while 
its electrical functionality is made drastically different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a proof-of-concept example, we have synthesized and designed
 a metamaterial shell that behaves simultaneously as a thermal concentrator and an electrical invisibility 
 cloak. In such a shell, the thermal and electrical currents follow markedly different paths, 
 with the former concentrating in the inner region and the latter circumventing that region, as schematized
 in the figure top panel. The bottom panel shows instead the thermal and electrical responses, which exhibit 
 the expected behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the results of this study are based on theory and numerical simulations, 
they do indicate that practical realization of these metamaterials should be within 
reach of current fabrication technologies. Our numerical simulations indeed show that they 
can be fabricated by means of small sub-blocks made of realistic materials, 
such as aluminum nitride and silver conductive epoxies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such design may be considered as a first step towards a more general 
 framework that could be defined as “transformation-multiphysics”, which may be in principle extended and applied 
 to a variety of electrical, magnetic, acoustic, and thermal systems in various combinations, 
 and may be integrated in advanced materials, spanning multiple orders of magnitude in material scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides serving as a proof-of-principle, the independent manipulation of electrical and thermal currents 
 is also very important from the application viewpoint.
 One particularly intriguing application is the engineering of thermoelectric materials, 
 which hold great promises for energy recycling, by converting waste heat 
 (e.g., generated by the CPU of a computer) into additional electrical power. 
 For these materials, the independent control of electrical and thermal conductivities is of paramount importance, 
 and it may affect the figure of merit in ways unexplored in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014&quot;&gt;Moccia, M., Castaldi, G., Savo, S., Sato, Y., &amp;amp; Galdi, V. (2014). Independent manipulation of heat and electrical current via bifunctional metamaterials. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review X&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;4&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(2), 021025.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevX.4.021025&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;Spatial tailoring of the material constitutive properties is a well-known strategy to mold the local flow of given observables in different physical domains. Coordinate-transformation-based methods (e.g., transformation optics) offer a powerful and systematic approach to design anisotropic, spatially inhomogeneous artificial materials (metamaterials) capable of precisely manipulating wave-based (electromagnetic, acoustic, elastic) as well as diffusion-based (heat) phenomena in a desired fashion. However, as versatile as these approaches have been, most designs have thus far been limited to serving single-target functionalities in a given physical domain. Here, we present a step towards a “transformation multiphysics” framework that allows independent and simultaneous manipulation of multiple physical phenomena. As a proof of principle of this new scheme, we design and synthesize (in terms of realistic material constituents) a metamaterial shell that simultaneously behaves as a thermal concentrator and an electrical “invisibility cloak.” Our numerical results open up intriguing possibilities in the largely unexplored phase space of multifunctional metadevices, with a wide variety of potential applications to electrical, magnetic, acoustic, and thermal scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ112_PRX_4_021025_2014,
  title = {Independent manipulation of heat and electrical current via bifunctional metamaterials},
  author = {Moccia, Massimo and Castaldi, Giuseppe and Savo, Salvatore and Sato, Yuki and Galdi, Vincenzo},
  journal = {Physical Review X},
  volume = {4},
  issue = {2},
  pages = {021025},
  numpages = {14},
  year = {2014},
  month = may,
  publisher = {American Physical Society},
  doi = {10.1103/PhysRevX.4.021025},
  url = {http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.4.021025}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="metamaterials" /><category term="multiphysics" /><category term="cloaking" /><category term="thermoelectrics" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Optical fiber meta-tips</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/meta-tip" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optical fiber meta-tips" /><published>2017-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/meta-tip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/meta-tip">&lt;p&gt;Metasurfaces are 2-D implementations of metamaterials that are eliciting a growing attention in view the
inherent simplification in the fabrication process, by comparison with three-dimensional bulk nanostructures, and their 
compatibility with on-chip photonics. Taking inspiration from reflect/transmit-array radio-frequency antennas,
typical metasurface implementations rely on two-dimensional arrays of resonators which can locally impress abrupt phase and 
amplitude variations in an impinging wavefront, while maintaining a deeply-subwavelength profile by exploiting
plasmonic or high-index dielectric nanoantennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A possible development of strategic importance is the metasurface integration with fiber-
optics technology. This fits naturally within the recently emerged &lt;em&gt;lab-on-fiber&lt;/em&gt; technology, which envisions the
integration of optical fibers with nanophotonic and/or nanoplasmonic platforms enabling for nanoscale control of
light, thereby substantially expanding the functionalities of conventional and specialty fibers, with potential
applications ranging from optical processing to environmental monitoring, life science, safety and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.optoelectronics.ing.unisannio.it/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;layout=edit&amp;amp;id=100&quot;&gt;Andrea Cusano&lt;/a&gt;’s Group (University of Sannio),
we presented in [&lt;a href=&quot;#Principe-2016&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;] a first proof-of-principle example of a “meta-tip”, featuring 
a plasmonic metasurface integrated on the tip of an optical fiber, as schematized in the figure top panel.
The metasurface was designed so as to impress a linear phase (constant gradient) profile along an in-plane direction. As
typical for metasurface implementations based on a single layer of plasmonic nanoantennas, in order to achieve a full 
 excursion in the desired phase distribution for the transmitted field, we exploited a polarization-conversion mechanism. 
 In our case, a light beam paraxially impinging from the fiber core is split into an
ordinary and an anomalous beam, with the former essentially unaffected in shape, direction and polarization,
and the latter steered of an angle \(\theta_t\) along the gradient direction and orthogonally polarized. 
The figure top panel also illustrates the generalized Snell’s laws governing this phenomenon, as well as 
unit-cell of our Babinet-inverted metasurface, consisting of a rectangular aperture nanoantenna 
(rotated by an angle of 45° in the x-y plane) in a 50nm-thick gold film.
The center panels show the scanning-electron-microscope images of a meta-tip prototype fabricated in
collaboration with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sles11web.imm.cnr.it&quot;&gt;CNR Institute for Microelectronics and Microsystems&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uttp.enea.it/index.asp?p=12&amp;amp;t=Materiali%20e%20nuove%20tecnologie&quot;&gt;ENEA UTTP-MDB&lt;/a&gt;, via 
focused-ion-beam milling.
The bottom panels illustrates the results of the far-field characterization, without polarization control. 
There is a very good correspondence between the main and secondary peaks in the
numerical profiles with those in the experimental intensity maps, from which we can unambiguously associate the main peak
with the ordinary (co-polarized) beam, and the secondary peak with the anomalous beam. Moreover, the numerically-computed total field intensities averaged over x- and y-polarized illuminations (dashed magenta
curves) are in fairly good agreement with the experimental intensity profiles (solid black curves).
We also carried out polarization-controlled measurements, which confirmed the theoretically predicted response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proof-of-principle meta-tip demonstration paves the way to the integration of the exceptional field-manipulation
capabilities enabled by metasurfaces within the emerging lab-on-fiber technologies. Also of great interest is the excitation
of novel type of surface waves for label-free &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/MTM_optical-sensing&quot;&gt;sensing applications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Principe-2016&quot;&gt;Principe, M., Consales, M., Micco, A., Crescitelli, A., Castaldi, G., Esposito, E., … Cusano, A. (2016, September). &lt;i&gt;Optical fiber meta-tips&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;Principe-2016-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#Principe-2016-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    

    

    
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aap.nature-lsa.cn:8080/cms/accessory/files/AAP-lsa2016226.pdf&quot;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
      
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;Principe-2016-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@unpublished{Principe-2016,
  author = {Principe, M. and Consales, M. and Micco, A. and Crescitelli, A. and Castaldi, G. and Esposito, E. and Ferrara, V. La and Cutolo, A. and Galdi, V. and Cusano, A.},
  title = {Optical fiber meta-tips},
  year = {2016},
  month = sep,
  preprint = {http://aap.nature-lsa.cn:8080/cms/accessory/files/AAP-lsa2016226.pdf}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="metamaterials" /><category term="metasurfaces" /><category term="optical fibers" /><category term="plasmonics" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our paper on non-Hermitian metasurfaces accepted in PRB</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/PRB-paper-NH-MS-accepted" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our paper on non-Hermitian metasurfaces accepted in PRB" /><published>2017-02-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/PRB-paper-NH-MS-accepted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/PRB-paper-NH-MS-accepted">&lt;p&gt;Our paper on “Magnified imaging based on non-Hermitian nonlocal cylindrical
 metasurfaces,”
in collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://users.ece.utexas.edu/~aalu/)&quot;&gt;Andrea Alù&lt;/a&gt;’s Group (University of Texas at Austin),
has been accepted for publication in &lt;em&gt;Physical Review B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1702.04101&quot;&gt;arXiv preprint&lt;/a&gt; is available.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="non-Hermitian" /><category term="metasurfaces" /><summary type="html">Our paper on “Magnified imaging based on non-Hermitian nonlocal cylindrical
 metasurfaces,”
in collaboration with Andrea Alù’s Group (University of Texas at Austin),
has been accepted for publication in Physical Review B.

An arXiv preprint is available.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/news/NH-MS.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ray-chaotic “billiard” cavities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/billiard-cavities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ray-chaotic “billiard” cavities" /><published>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/billiard-cavities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/billiard-cavities">&lt;p&gt;Ray chaos, i.e., exponential sensitivity of ray trajectories to launching conditions, 
could intuitively be expected in very complex and cluttered propagation scenarios 
(e.g., urban areas). Remarkably, it can also be observed in relatively simple (but coordinate-non-separable) 
structures that give  rise to multiple reflections, focusing, and defocusing, such as 
homogeneously filled “billiard-shaped” enclosures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], by revisiting a body of results from quantum physics (classical vs. quantum chaos),
we emphasized possible implications of internal ray chaos for high-frequency wave dynamics (“ray-chaotic footprints”).
In the time-harmonic high-frequency limit, ray-chaotically-inclined systems tend to exhibit behaviors that differ fundamentally 
from those observed in ray-regular geometries.
For instance, in connection with the eigenvalues, in regular billiards 
the normalized neighboring spacing statistics follow a Poisson probability density function (PDF), 
whereas in completely ray-chaotic billiards, they turn out to be accurately modeled by a Wigner-Rayleigh PDF.
In connection with the eigenfunctions, in regular billiards, 
the wavefield at each point results from the superposition of plane waves (rays) from a finite number of 
possible directions, whereas in completely ray-chaotic billiards it is expected to be a superposition of 
a multitude of plane waves, with fixed wavevector amplitude, and uniform direction and phase distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], we carried out a full-wave investigation of 
short-pulse electromagnetic wavepacket propagation in ray-chaotic enclosures, 
via a numerical approach based on the finite difference time domain (FDTD) method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure top panel shows the quarter-Sinai-stadium configuration considered, with a 
typical space-filling ray trajectory (after 250 reflections), and a map illustrating 
the uniform filling of the phase-space (reflection position vs. direction).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom panels show instead the temporal evolution of a short-pulsed wavepacket launched in the cavity.
While bouncing around the walls, along the ray path skeleton, the wavepacket undergoes focusing at the concave 
curved wall and natural spreading elsewhere (including straight-wall reflection), 
progressively losing its initial space-time localization. 
At a sufficiently long time, the wavepacket has already uniformly covered the entire enclosure, and the initially localized energy 
is spread across the mode spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results from statistical analysis of the late-time spatial field distributions are 
consistent with the assumption of a random pulsed plane-wave model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These results may find important applications
to wideband electromagnetic interference and/or compatibility testbeds
(whereby an equipment under test may be subjected to a “pulse
shower” illumination with characteristics largely independent
of its location, orientation, shape and constitutive properties),
as well as the synthetic emulation of multi-path wireless channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005&quot;&gt;Galdi, V., Pinto, I. M., &amp;amp; Felsen, L. B. (2005). Wave propagation in ray-chaotic enclosures: paradigms, oddities and examples. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Antennas and Propagation Magazine&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;47&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(1), 62–81.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/MAP.2005.1436220&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;Ray chaos, characterized by eventual exponential divergence of originally nearby multi-bounce ray trajectories, is an intriguing phenomenon. It can be observed in several electromagnetic wave propagation scenarios: both very complex (e.g., urban areas) and very simple (e.g., a stadium-shaped cavity) scenarios. This paper contains a compact review of known results on wave propagation in ray-chaotic scenarios. Attention is focused principally on two-dimensional simple paradigms of internal ray chaos (“ray-chaotic billiards”), with emphasis on possible implications for high-frequency wave dynamics (“ray-chaotic footprints”). General concepts, tools, and numerical examples are discussed, and their potential relevance to current challenges in electromagnetic engineering is noted.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ30_IEEE_APMAG_47_62_2005,
  author = {Galdi, V. and Pinto, I. M. and Felsen, L. B.},
  journal = {IEEE Antennas and Propagation Magazine},
  title = {Wave propagation in ray-chaotic enclosures: paradigms, oddities and examples},
  year = {2005},
  volume = {47},
  number = {1},
  pages = {62--81},
  keywords = {chaos;electromagnetic wave propagation;electromagnetic engineering;electromagnetic wave propagation;exponential divergence;high-frequency wave dynamics;internal ray chaos;multi-bounce ray trajectory;ray-chaotic enclosure;wave propagation;Aerodynamics;Aerospace engineering;Chaos;Electromagnetic propagation;Fluid dynamics;Geometrical optics;Laser cavity resonators;Mechanical engineering;Optical propagation;Urban areas},
  doi = {10.1109/MAP.2005.1436220},
  issn = {1045-9243},
  month = feb
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012&quot;&gt;Castaldi, G., Galdi, V., &amp;amp; Pinto, I. M. (2012). Short-pulsed wavepacket propagation in ray-chaotic enclosures. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;60&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(8), 3827–3837.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2012.2201126&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;Wave propagation in ray-chaotic scenarios, characterized by exponential sensitivity to ray-launching conditions, is a topic of significant interest, with deep phenomenological implications and important applications, ranging from optical components and devices to time-reversal focusing/sensing schemes. Against a background of available results that are largely focused on the time-harmonic regime, we deal here with short-pulsed wavepacket propagation in a ray-chaotic enclosure. For this regime, we propose a rigorous analytical framework based on a short-pulsed random-plane-wave statistical representation, and check its predictions against the results from finite-difference-time-domain numerical simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ100_IEEE_TAP_60_3827_2012,
  author = {Castaldi, G. and Galdi, V. and Pinto, I. M.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {Short-pulsed wavepacket propagation in ray-chaotic enclosures},
  year = {2012},
  volume = {60},
  number = {8},
  pages = {3827--3837},
  keywords = {chaos;electromagnetic wave propagation;statistical analysis;ray launching condition;ray-chaotic enclosures;short pulsed random plane wave statistical representation;short pulsed wavepacket propagation;time reversal focusing;time reversal sensing;time-harmonic regime;Apertures;Finite difference methods;Geometry;Numerical models;Time domain analysis;Trajectory;Vectors;Plane waves;random fields;ray chaos;short pulses},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2012.2201126},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = aug
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="ray chaos" /><category term="cavities" /><category term="high-frequency" /><category term="short-pulse" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aperiodic-tiling antenna arrays</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/aperiodic-tiling_arrays" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aperiodic-tiling antenna arrays" /><published>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/aperiodic-tiling_arrays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/aperiodic-tiling_arrays">&lt;p&gt;Our Group has been among the pioneers in the application of aperiodically ordered structures in electromagnetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], 
in collaboration with the late Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leopold_B._Felsen&quot;&gt;Leo Felsen&lt;/a&gt; (Boston University),
 we first introduced the concept of “aperiodic tiling” in the theory of antenna arrays. 
This study clarifies some fundamental theoretical aspects related to the effects of “order” and “symmetry” 
in the radiation characteristics. Moreover, it identifies certain aperiodic configurations particularly 
interesting in terms of bandwidth and sidelobe level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure illustrates the inflection rule to generate a particular (Danzer) aperiodic tiling (top), and the 
corresponding radiation spectrum (bottom), from which it can be observed a 14-fold rotational symmetry and the absence of grating lobes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major complication that arises when dealing with aperiodic structures, is the lack of the typical 
analytical tools available for periodic geometries.
In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], with specific reference to a 
“modified-Fibonacci” &lt;em&gt;quasi-periodic&lt;/em&gt; sequence, we showed a
two-scale generalization of the standard Poisson summation formula for periodic arrays. 
This allows for a “quasi-Floquet” analytic parameterization of the radiated field, 
which provides instructive insights into some of the basic wave mechanisms associated with quasi-periodic order. 
These results were also extended to account for the presence of a dielectric substrate [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], we explored various configurations 
generated by Rudin-Shapiro sequences, which constitute one of the simplest conceivable 
examples of deterministic aperiodic geometries featuring random-like (dis)order. 
In particular, we showed that these might find interesting applications to the synthesis of
&lt;em&gt;omnidirectional&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;thinned&lt;/em&gt; arrays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], we studied 
the plane-wave scattering from general one-dimensional aperiodically ordered 
strip-array geometries based on two-symbol substitution rules. By exploiting theoretical results from solid-state physics 
and discrete geometry, we showed that a wealth of scattering signatures, 
with (sometime counter-intuitive) spectral characteristics ranging from quasiperiodic to quasirandom, 
can be obtained via judicious exploitation of the additional geometrical and/or constitutive degrees of 
freedom available in aperiodic configurations. In particular, we highlighted the role played by the substitution 
rule (and, specifically, the arithmetical properties of the associated substitution matrix), the scale-ratio, 
the element scattering responde, and the array size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005&quot;&gt;Pierro, V., Galdi, V., Castaldi, G., Pinto, I. M., &amp;amp; Felsen, L. B. (2005). Radiation properties of planar antenna arrays based on certain categories of aperiodic tilings. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;53&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(2), 635–644.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2004.841287&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;Two-dimensional aperiodic tilings are collections of polygons, devoid of any translational symmetries, capable of covering a plane without gaps and overlaps. Although aperiodic, these structures can exhibit order and symmetry in an extended sense. In this paper, we study the radiation properties of planar antenna arrays based on certain categories of two-dimensional aperiodic tilings that illustrate diverse aspects of aperiodic order. Background material on aperiodic tilings and their known electromagnetic properties is reviewed. Results are illustrated to highlight the effects of aperiodic order in the antenna array radiation properties. Potential applications are also envisaged&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ28_IEEE_TAP_53_635_2005,
  author = {Pierro, V. and Galdi, V. and Castaldi, G. and Pinto, I. M. and Felsen, L. B.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {Radiation properties of planar antenna arrays based on certain categories of aperiodic tilings},
  year = {2005},
  volume = {53},
  number = {2},
  pages = {635--644},
  keywords = {antenna radiation patterns;electromagnetic waves;periodic structures;planar antenna arrays;quasicrystals;diverse aspect;electromagnetic property;planar antenna array;potential application;radiation property;translational symmetry;two-dimensional aperiodic tiling;Antenna arrays;Design engineering;Electromagnetic radiation;Electromagnetic scattering;Geometry;Periodic structures;Physics computing;Planar arrays;Power engineering and energy;Power engineering computing;Antenna arrays;aperiodic tilings;quasi-crystals;radiation},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2004.841287},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = feb
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005&quot;&gt;Galdi, V., Castaldi, G., Pierro, V., Pinto, I. M., &amp;amp; Felsen, L. B. (2005). Parameterizing quasi-periodicity: generalized Poisson summation and its application to modified-Fibonacci antenna arrays. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;53&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(6), 2044–2053.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2005.848514&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;The fairly recent discovery of “quasi-crystals”, whose X-ray diffraction patterns reveal certain peculiar features which do not conform with spatial periodicity, has motivated studies of the wave-dynamical implications of &quot;aperiodic order&quot;. Within the context of the radiation properties of antenna arrays, an instructive novel (canonical) example of wave interactions with quasi-periodic order is illustrated here for one-dimensional array configurations based on the “modified-Fibonacci” sequence, with utilization of a two-scale generalization of the standard Poisson summation formula for periodic arrays. This allows for a “quasi-Floquet” analytic parameterization of the radiated field, which provides instructive insights into some of the basic wave mechanisms associated with quasi-periodic order, highlighting similarities and differences with the periodic case. Examples are shown for quasi-periodic infinite and spatially-truncated arrays, with brief discussion of computational issues and potential applications.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ32_IEEE_TAP_53_2044_2005,
  author = {Galdi, V. and Castaldi, G. and Pierro, V. and Pinto, I. M. and Felsen, L. B.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {Parameterizing quasi-periodicity: generalized Poisson summation and its application to modified-Fibonacci antenna arrays},
  year = {2005},
  volume = {53},
  number = {6},
  pages = {2044--2053},
  keywords = {Fibonacci sequences;antenna arrays;antenna radiation patterns;quasicrystals;stochastic processes;antenna arrays;modified-Fibonacci sequence;one-dimensional array configuration;periodic arrays;quasiFloquet analytic parameterization;quasicrystals;quasiperiodic order;standard Poisson summation formula;Antenna arrays;Electromagnetic devices;Electromagnetic diffraction;Frequency selective surfaces;Geometry;Helium;Passband;Photonic band gap;Two dimensional displays;X-ray diffraction;Antenna arrays;Fibonacci sequence;aperiodic order;generalized Poisson summation},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2005.848514},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = jun
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007&quot;&gt;Castaldi, G., Galdi, V., Pierro, V., &amp;amp; Pinto, I. M. (2007). Radiation from Fibonacci-type quasiperiodic arrays on dielectric substrates. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Electromagnetic Waves and Applications&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;21&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(9), 1231–1245.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1163/156939307794731187&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt; We present a simple prototype study of electromagnetic radiation by a one-dimensional quasiperiodic Fibonacci-type array laid on a grounded dielectric slab, extending our previous free-space studies. Analytic parameterization of the interaction between aperiodic-order-induced &quot;quasi-Floquet&quot; waves and slab-induced surface/leaky-waves is addressed, for infinite and truncated arrays, via generalized Poisson summation and uniform asymptotics. Accuracy and computational effectiveness of the proposed parameterizations are assessed via numerical comparisons against an independently-generated reference solution (element-by-element synthesis). &lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ42_JEWA_21_1231_2007,
  author = {Castaldi, G. and Galdi, V. and Pierro, V. and Pinto, I. M.},
  title = {Radiation from Fibonacci-type quasiperiodic arrays on dielectric substrates},
  journal = {Journal of Electromagnetic Waves and Applications},
  volume = {21},
  number = {9},
  pages = {1231--1245},
  year = {2007},
  month = sep,
  doi = {10.1163/156939307794731187},
  url = { http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1163/156939307794731187}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005&quot;&gt;Galdi, V., Pierro, V., Castaldi, G., Pinto, I. M., &amp;amp; Felsen, L. B. (2005). Radiation properties of one-dimensional random-like antenna arrays based on Rudin-Shapiro sequences. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;53&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(11), 3568–3575.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2005.858863&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;The development of exotic new materials, such as metamaterials, has created strong interest within the electromagnetics (EM) community for possible new phenomenologies and device applications, with particular attention to periodicity-induced phenomena, such as photonic bandgaps. Within this context, motivated by the fairly recent discovery in X-ray crystallography of “quasi-crystals”, whose diffraction patterns display unusual characteristics that are associated with “aperiodic order”, we have undertaken a systematic study of how these exotic effects manifest themselves in the radiation properties of aperiodically configured antenna arrays. The background for these studies, with promising example configurations, has been reported in a previous publication [V. Pierro et al., IEEE Trans. Antennas Propag., vol. 53, pp. 635-644, Feb. 2005]. In this paper, we pay attention to various configurations generated by Rudin-Shapiro (RS) sequences, which constitute one of the simplest conceivable examples of deterministic aperiodic geometries featuring random-like (dis)order. After presentation and review of relevant background material, the radiation properties of one-dimensional RS-based antenna arrays are analyzed, followed by illustrative numerical parametric studies to validate the theoretical models. Design parameters and potential practical applications are also given attention.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ33_IEEE_TAP_53_3568_2005,
  author = {Galdi, V. and Pierro, V. and Castaldi, G. and Pinto, I. M. and Felsen, L. B.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {Radiation properties of one-dimensional random-like antenna arrays based on Rudin-Shapiro sequences},
  year = {2005},
  volume = {53},
  number = {11},
  pages = {3568--3575},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2005.858863},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = nov
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007&quot;&gt;Galdi, V., Castaldi, G., Pierro, V., Pinto, I. M., &amp;amp; Felsen, L. B. (2007). Scattering properties of one-dimensional aperiodically-ordered strip arrays based on two-symbol substitutional sequences. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;55&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(6), 1554–1563.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2007.897228&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;This paper is concerned with a study of the two-dimensional (2-D) time-harmonic scattering by aperiodically-ordered 1-D planar strip arrays based on two-symbol substitutional sequences, under Kirchhoff physical-optics approximation. In this connection, theoretical results from solid-state physics, dwelling on concepts from discrete geometry and number theory, are briefly reviewed and applied to the characterization of the scattering signatures of the above physical configuration. Parametric studies are presented in order to flesh out some of the above concepts and to highlight wave-features which are thought as being representative of a fairly broad class of regular non-periodic scatterers. Potential applications are also envisaged.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ39_IEEE_TAP_55_1554_2007,
  author = {Galdi, V. and Castaldi, G. and Pierro, V. and Pinto, I. M. and Felsen, L. B.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {Scattering properties of one-dimensional aperiodically-ordered strip arrays based on two-symbol substitutional sequences},
  year = {2007},
  volume = {55},
  number = {6},
  pages = {1554--1563},
  keywords = {electromagnetic wave scattering;quasicrystals;symbolic substitution;1D aperiodically-ordered strip arrays;1D planar strip arrays;2D time-harmonic scattering;Kirchhoff physical-optics approximation;nonperiodic scatterers;scattering properties;solid-state physics;two-symbol substitutional sequences;wave-features;Electrodynamics;Electromagnetic scattering;Geometry;Helium;Parametric study;Particle scattering;Periodic structures;Physics;Solid state circuits;Two dimensional displays;Aperiodic order;quasicrystals;scattering;substitutional sequences},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2007.897228},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = jun
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="aperiodic tilings" /><category term="antenna arrays" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Optimized mirror coatings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/GW-coating" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optimized mirror coatings" /><published>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/GW-coating</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/GW-coating">&lt;p&gt;For second-generation gravitational-wave interferometric detectors such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.advancedligo.mit.edu&quot;&gt;Advanced LIGO&lt;/a&gt;, 
the thermal noise of the test mass mirror coatings is a significant limit in a critical midband around 100 Hz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optical cavities at the heart of the length-sensing mechanism of gravitational wave interferometers 
use mirrors made with multilayer dielectric coatings to produce the high reflectivities that are required.
The conventional design of high-reflectivity multilayer dielectric coating consists of quarter-wavelength alternating layers 
made of silica (low-index) and tantala (high-index) materials. Such design, though optimal from the reflectivity viewpoint, 
does not minimize the thermal noise since there is a substantial difference in the mechanical loss of 
the two material constituents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#ISI-000241947200007&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], we proposed a systematic procedure for designing minimal-noise 
coatings featuring a prescribed reflectivity. Such design is based on a periodic stack of 
identical high/low index ‘‘doublets,’’ with total thickness of half-wavelength and optimized material fractions, 
with the exception of the terminal (top/bottom) layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirrors based on such a design were fabricated 
at the Laboratoire des Matériaux Avancés (Lyon, France) and experimentally characterized by measuring 
the broadband noise floor of the Thermal Noise
Interferometer (TNI) at the California Institute of Technology [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure shows the optimized design (top), and the measured thermal noise (bottom) 
compared with the standard quarter-wavelength design.
The measurements indicated a reduction in thermal noise in line with modeling predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our optimized mirror coatings have been implemented in Advanced LIGO [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], and have contributed 
to attain the required strain sensitivity for the direct detection of gravitational waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ISI-000241947200007&quot;&gt;Agresti, J., Castaldi, G., DeSalvo, R., Galdi, V., Pierro, V., &amp;amp; Pinto, I. M. (2006). Optimized multilayer dielectric mirror coatings for gravitational wave
   interferometers. In M. J. Ellison (Ed.), &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of SPIE&lt;/i&gt; (Vol. 6286, p. 628608). Advances in Thin-Film Coatings for Optical Applications
   III, SPIE Photonics West, San Diego, CA, USA, Aug. 13-14, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;ISI-000241947200007-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#ISI-000241947200007-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.678977&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;ISI-000241947200007-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{ISI-000241947200007,
  author = {Agresti, Juri and Castaldi, Giuseppe and DeSalvo, Riccardo and Galdi, Vincenzo and Pierro, Vincenzo and Pinto, Innocenzo M.},
  editor = {Ellison, MJ},
  title = {Optimized multilayer dielectric mirror coatings for gravitational wave
     interferometers},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of SPIE},
  year = {2006},
  month = aug,
  volume = {6286},
  organization = {Advances in Thin-Film Coatings for Optical Applications
     III, SPIE Photonics West, San Diego, CA, USA, Aug. 13-14, 2006},
  doi = {10.1117/12.678977},
  pages = {628608}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010&quot;&gt;Villar, A. E., Black, E. D., DeSalvo, R., Libbrecht, K. G., Michel, C., Morgado, N., … Taurasi, I. (2010). Measurement of thermal noise in multilayer coatings with optimized layer thickness. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review D&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;81&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(12), 122001.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.81.122001&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;A standard quarter-wavelength multilayer optical coating will produce the highest reflectivity for a given number of coating layers, but in general it will not yield the lowest thermal noise for a prescribed reflectivity. Coatings with the layer thicknesses optimized to minimize thermal noise could be useful in future generation interferometric gravitational wave detectors where coating thermal noise is expected to limit the sensitivity of the instrument. We present the results of direct measurements of the thermal noise of a standard quarter-wavelength coating and a low noise optimized coating. The measurements indicate a reduction in thermal noise in line with modeling predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ86_PRD_81_122001_2010,
  title = {Measurement of thermal noise in multilayer coatings with optimized layer thickness},
  author = {Villar, Akira E. and Black, Eric D. and DeSalvo, Riccardo and Libbrecht, Kenneth G. and Michel, Christophe and Morgado, Nazario and Pinard, Laurent and Pinto, Innocenzo M. and Pierro, Vincenzo and Galdi, Vincenzo and Principe, Maria and Taurasi, Ilaria},
  journal = {Physical Review D},
  volume = {81},
  issue = {12},
  pages = {122001},
  numpages = {8},
  year = {2010},
  month = jun,
  publisher = {American Physical Society},
  doi = {10.1103/PhysRevD.81.122001},
  url = {http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.81.122001}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016&quot;&gt;Martynov, D. V., Hall, E. D., Abbott, B. P., Abbott, R., Abbott, T. D., Adams, C., … Zweizig, J. (2016). Sensitivity of the Advanced LIGO detectors at the beginning of gravitational wave astronomy. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review D&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;93&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(11), 112004.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.93.112004&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;The Laser Interferometer Gravitational Wave Observatory (LIGO) consists of two widely separated 4 km laser interferometers designed to detect gravitational waves from distant astrophysical sources in the frequency range from 10 Hz to 10 kHz. The first observation run of the Advanced LIGO detectors started in September 2015 and ended in January 2016. A strain sensitivity of better than
&amp;lt;img style=’vertical-align:middle;’ src=&quot;/assets/images/equations/imgtemp_x9wfkh-1.svg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&amp;gt;  
was achieved around 100 Hz. Understanding both the fundamental and the technical noise sources was critical for increasing the astrophysical strain sensitivity. The average distance at which coalescing binary black hole systems with individual masses of 30 
  \(M_⊙\)could be detected above a signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) of 8 was 1.3 Gpc, and the range for binary neutron star inspirals was about 75 Mpc. With respect to the initial detectors, the observable volume of the Universe increased by a factor 69 and 43, respectively. These improvements helped Advanced LIGO to detect the gravitational wave signal from the binary black hole coalescence, known as GW150914.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ119_PRD_93_112004_2016,
  title = {Sensitivity of the Advanced LIGO detectors at the beginning of gravitational wave astronomy},
  author = {Martynov, D. V. and Hall, E. D. and Abbott, B. P. and Abbott, R. and Abbott, T. D. and Adams, C. and Adhikari, R. X. and Anderson, R. A. and Anderson, S. B. and Arai, K. and Arain, M. A. and Aston, S. M. and Austin, L. and Ballmer, S. W. and Barbet, M. and Barker, D. and Barr, B. and Barsotti, L. and Bartlett, J. and Barton, M. A. and Bartos, I. and Batch, J. C. and Bell, A. S. and Belopolski, I. and Bergman, J. and Betzwieser, J. and Billingsley, G. and Birch, J. and Biscans, S. and Biwer, C. and Black, E. and Blair, C. D. and Bogan, C. and Bork, R. and Bridges, D. O. and Brooks, A. F. and Celerier, C. and Ciani, G. and Clara, F. and Cook, D. and Countryman, S. T. and Cowart, M. J. and Coyne, D. C. and Cumming, A. and Cunningham, L. and Damjanic, M. and Dannenberg, R. and Danzmann, K. and Costa, C. F. Da Silva and Daw, E. J. and DeBra, D. and DeRosa, R. T. and DeSalvo, R. and Dooley, K. L. and Doravari, S. and Driggers, J. C. and Dwyer, S. E. and Effler, A. and Etzel, T. and Evans, M. and Evans, T. M. and Factourovich, M. and Fair, H. and Feldbaum, D. and Fisher, R. P. and Foley, S. and Frede, M. and Fritschel, P. and Frolov, V. V. and Fulda, P. and Fyffe, M. and Galdi, V. and Giaime, J. A. and Giardina, K. D. and Gleason, J. R. and Goetz, R. and Gras, S. and Gray, C. and Greenhalgh, R. J. S. and Grote, H. and Guido, C. J. and Gushwa, K. E. and Gustafson, E. K. and Gustafson, R. and Hammond, G. and Hanks, J. and Hanson, J. and Hardwick, T. and Harry, G. M. and Heefner, J. and Heintze, M. C. and Heptonstall, A. W. and Hoak, D. and Hough, J. and Ivanov, A. and Izumi, K. and Jacobson, M. and James, E. and Jones, R. and Kandhasamy, S. and Karki, S. and Kasprzack, M. and Kaufer, S. and Kawabe, K. and Kells, W. and Kijbunchoo, N. and King, E. J. and King, P. J. and Kinzel, D. L. and Kissel, J. S. and Kokeyama, K. and Korth, W. Z. and Kuehn, G. and Kwee, P. and Landry, M. and Lantz, B. and Le Roux, A. and Levine, B. M. and Lewis, J. B. and Lhuillier, V. and Lockerbie, N. A. and Lormand, M. and Lubinski, M. J. and Lundgren, A. P. and MacDonald, T. and MacInnis, M. and Macleod, D. M. and Mageswaran, M. and Mailand, K. and M\'arka, S. and M\'arka, Z. and Markosyan, A. S. and Maros, E. and Martin, I. W. and Martin, R. M. and Marx, J. N. and Mason, K. and Massinger, T. J. and Matichard, F. and Mavalvala, N. and McCarthy, R. and McClelland, D. E. and McCormick, S. and McIntyre, G. and McIver, J. and Merilh, E. L. and Meyer, M. S. and Meyers, P. M. and Miller, J. and Mittleman, R. and Moreno, G. and Mueller, C. L. and Mueller, G. and Mullavey, A. and Munch, J. and Nuttall, L. K. and Oberling, J. and O'Dell, J. and Oppermann, P. and Oram, Richard J. and O'Reilly, B. and Osthelder, C. and Ottaway, D. J. and Overmier, H. and Palamos, J. R. and Paris, H. R. and Parker, W. and Patrick, Z. and Pele, A. and Penn, S. and Phelps, M. and Pickenpack, M. and Pierro, V. and Pinto, I. and Poeld, J. and Principe, M. and Prokhorov, L. and Puncken, O. and Quetschke, V. and Quintero, E. A. and Raab, F. J. and Radkins, H. and Raffai, P. and Ramet, C. R. and Reed, C. M. and Reid, S. and Reitze, D. H. and Robertson, N. A. and Rollins, J. G. and Roma, V. J. and Romie, J. H. and Rowan, S. and Ryan, K. and Sadecki, T. and Sanchez, E. J. and Sandberg, V. and Sannibale, V. and Savage, R. L. and Schofield, R. M. S. and Schultz, B. and Schwinberg, P. and Sellers, D. and Sevigny, A. and Shaddock, D. A. and Shao, Z. and Shapiro, B. and Shawhan, P. and Shoemaker, D. H. and Sigg, D. and Slagmolen, B. J. J. and Smith, J. R. and Smith, M. R. and Smith-Lefebvre, N. D. and Sorazu, B. and Staley, A. and Stein, A. J. and Stochino, A. and Strain, K. A. and Taylor, R. and Thomas, M. and Thomas, P. and Thorne, K. A. and Thrane, E. and Torrie, C. I. and Traylor, G. and Vajente, G. and Valdes, G. and van Veggel, A. A. and Vargas, M. and Vecchio, A. and Veitch, P. J. and Venkateswara, K. and Vo, T. and Vorvick, C. and Waldman, S. J. and Walker, M. and Ward, R. L. and Warner, J. and Weaver, B. and Weiss, R. and Welborn, T. and We\ss{}els, P. and Wilkinson, C. and Willems, P. A. and Williams, L. and Willke, B. and Winkelmann, L. and Wipf, C. C. and Worden, J. and Wu, G. and Yamamoto, H. and Yancey, C. C. and Yu, H. and Zhang, L. and Zucker, M. E. and Zweizig, J.},
  journal = {Physical Review D},
  volume = {93},
  issue = {11},
  pages = {112004},
  numpages = {19},
  year = {2016},
  month = jun,
  publisher = {American Physical Society},
  doi = {10.1103/PhysRevD.93.112004},
  url = {http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.93.112004}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="gravitational waves" /><category term="mirrors" /><category term="coatings" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Michele Scaravilli</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/team/michele-scaravilli" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Michele Scaravilli" /><published>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/team/michele-scaravilli</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/team/michele-scaravilli">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michele Scaravilli&lt;/strong&gt; was born in Caserta, Italy, on December 9, 1988.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He received his M.E. degree in Electrical Engineering (&lt;em&gt;summa cum laude&lt;/em&gt;) from the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unina.it/en_GB/home&quot;&gt;“Federico II” University of Naples&lt;/a&gt;, Italy, with a thesis project 
dealing with the design and optimization of an anti-intrusion microwave sensor based on a 
parallel-plate waveguide with deformable walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since June 2014, he has been a Ph.D. student in Information Technologies for Engineering​at the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unisannio.it/en&quot;&gt;University of Sannio&lt;/a&gt;, Benevento, Italy, working in 
the Fields &amp;amp; Waves Lab and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.optoelectronics.ing.unisannio.it&quot;&gt;Optoelectronics Group&lt;/a&gt;, 
under the joint supervision of Proff. &lt;a href=&quot;/people/vincenzo-galdi&quot;&gt;Vincenzo Galdi&lt;/a&gt; 
and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.optoelectronics.ing.unisannio.it/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;layout=edit&amp;amp;id=100&quot;&gt;Andrea Cusano&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His current research activity is focused on the design, numerical modeling and fabrication of novel 
label-free optical fiber nanoprobes based on the excitation of Bloch surface waves, as well as SERS probes.
More generally, his scientific interests include: plasmonics, photonic crystals, bio-photonics and optical fiber sensors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><summary type="html">Michele Scaravilli was born in Caserta, Italy, on December 9, 1988.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/team/michele-scaravilli.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Massimo Moccia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/team/massimo-moccia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Massimo Moccia" /><published>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/team/massimo-moccia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/team/massimo-moccia">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massimo Moccia&lt;/strong&gt; was born in Benevento, Italy on February 11, 1982.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He received the B.S. and M.S. degree in Telecommunications Engineering (&lt;em&gt;summa cum laude&lt;/em&gt;) from the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unisannio.it/en&quot;&gt;University of Sannio&lt;/a&gt;,
Benevento, Italy, in 2005 and 2007 respectively. During his study program, he was a visiting student at the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upv.es/index-en.html&quot;&gt;Polytechnic University of Valencia&lt;/a&gt; (2003-2004) and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upc.edu/?set_language=en&quot;&gt;Polytechnic 
University of Catalonia&lt;/a&gt; (2007). 
In 2008, he attended a postgraduate specialization course in “Technologies for micro and nano electronics” at the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.uniroma1.it&quot;&gt;“Sapienza” University of Rome&lt;/a&gt;. In 2012, he received the Ph.D. Degree in Information Engineering from the 
University of Sannio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2012, he has been working as a Postdoctoral Researcher at the University of Sannio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His current research activity is focused on the areas of electromagnetic and multiphysics metamaterials, RF devices, and antenna design
for satellite applications. In the past, he has also worked on superconductivity experiments, ferroelectric devices,
fiber-optics sensors, and nanotechnologies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><summary type="html">Massimo Moccia was born in Benevento, Italy on February 11, 1982.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/team/massimo-moccia.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ray-chaotic “pinball” scatterers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/pinball-scatterers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ray-chaotic “pinball” scatterers" /><published>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/pinball-scatterers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/pinball-scatterers">&lt;p&gt;Other intriguing examples of ray chaos can be found in &lt;em&gt;open&lt;/em&gt; configurations such as (n&amp;gt;3)-disk “pinballs”, 
or appropriately configured inhomogeneous refractive media with ray-trapping properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], 
in collaboration with the late Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leopold_B._Felsen&quot;&gt;Leo Felsen&lt;/a&gt; (Boston University),
we 
studied a two-dimensional test example of such an environment 
which embodies intimately coupled refractive wave-trapping and periodicity-induced multiple 
scattering phenomenologies, and which is amenable to explicit full-wave analysis. 
Though strictly nonchaotic, we demonstrated that under appropriate conditions 
the high-frequency wave dynamics exhibits 
trends toward irregularity and other peculiar characteristics; 
these features can be interpreted as “ray-chaotic footprints”, and they are usually not observed 
in geometries characterized by “regular” ray behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In [&lt;a href=&quot;#IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;vertical-align: baseline&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], we extended this study to
a cylindrical scatterer made of a perfectly electric-conducting azimuthally corrugated boundary 
coated by a radially inhomogeneous (ray-trapping) dielectric layer, as shown in the figure (top panel).
We showed that, for such configuration, ray dynamics is generally of “mixed type,” with the presence 
of both regular and chaotic regions in the phase space. It is possible to “tune” the 
parameter configuration (e.g., acting on the refractive index gradient) so as to render the dynamics strongly chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By relying on a full-wave solution (via a problem-matched semi-analytic technique), we studied
the monostatic (i.e., observed at backscattering direction) radar-cross-section (RCS) response, 
for ﬁxed incidence angle and various parametric conﬁgurations ranging from regular to chaotic ray dynamics, 
for various representative frequency and incidence conditions. 
As illustrated in the figure bottom panels, starting from the fairly regular response of a plain circular cylinder, 
it is observed how introducing either corrugations or graded-index-coating alone 
(i.e., preserving the ray-regular behavior) produces only smooth changes or the appearance of isolated peaks. 
Conversely, introducing both corrugation and graded-index-coating (which are both required for the onset of ray-chaos) 
produces increasingly complex RCS responses. In particular, the conﬁguration corresponding to ray-chaotic dynamics&lt;br /&gt;
exhibits a monostatic RCS response with very rapid and irregular frequency variations, and 
wide (up to three orders of magnitude) dynamic ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our results clearly indicate that electrically large ray-chaotically inclined conﬁgurations 
exhibit fairly complex monostatic and bistatic RCS responses, characterized by wide dynamic ranges 
and strong sensitivity on the frequency and incidence direction, which are fairly different 
from those observed in ray-regular conﬁgurations. Particularly intriguing from the application viewpoint 
is the possible exploitation of the inherent richness and complexity of the RCS signatures 
 in radar-counter-measure scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relevant-papers&quot;&gt;Relevant papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005&quot;&gt;Castaldi, G., Fiumara, V., Galdi, V., Pierro, V., Pinto, I. M., &amp;amp; Felsen, L. B. (2005). Ray-chaotic footprints in deterministic wave dynamics: a test model with coupled Floquet-type and ducted-type mode characteristics. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;53&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(2), 753–765.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2004.841296&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;Ray chaos, manifested by the exponential divergence of trajectories in an originally thin ray bundle, can occur even in linear electromagnetic propagation environments, due to the inherent nonlinearity of ray-tracing maps. In this paper, we present a novel (two-dimensional) test example of such an environment which embodies intimately coupled refractive wave-trapping and periodicity-induced multiple scattering phenomenologies, and which is amenable to explicit full-wave analysis. Though strictly nonchaotic, it is demonstrated that under appropriate conditions which are inferred from a comprehensive parametric database generated via the above-noted rigorous reference solution, the high-frequency wave dynamics exhibits trends toward irregularity and other peculiar characteristics; these features can be interpreted as “ray-chaotic footprints”, and they are usually not observed in geometries characterized by “regular” ray behavior. In this connection, known analogies from other disciplines (particularly quantum physics) are briefly reviewed and related to the proposed test configuration. Moreover, theoretical implications and open issues are discussed, and potential applications are conjectured.&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ29_IEEE_TAP_53_753_2005,
  author = {Castaldi, G. and Fiumara, V. and Galdi, V. and Pierro, V. and Pinto, I. M. and Felsen, L. B.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {Ray-chaotic footprints in deterministic wave dynamics: a test model with coupled Floquet-type and ducted-type mode characteristics},
  year = {2005},
  volume = {53},
  number = {2},
  pages = {753--765},
  keywords = {chaos;electromagnetic wave propagation;electromagnetic wave scattering;nonlinear dynamical systems;ray tracing;coupled Floquet-type characteristics;coupled refractive wave-trapping;deterministic wave dynamics;ducted-type mode characteristics;exponential trajectory divergence;full-wave analysis;linear electromagnetic propagation;multiple scattering phenomenology;parametric database generation;periodicity;ray tracing map;ray-chaotic footprint;Chaos;Character generation;Electromagnetic propagation;Electromagnetic refraction;Electromagnetic scattering;Particle scattering;Ray tracing;Spatial databases;Testing;Trajectory;Ducted-type modes;Floquet theory;ray chaos},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2004.841296},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = feb
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008&quot;&gt;Castaldi, G., Galdi, V., &amp;amp; Pinto, I. M. (2008). A study of ray-chaotic cylindrical scatterers. &lt;i&gt;IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;56&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(8), 2638–2648.&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008-abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;#IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008-bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

            
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAP.2008.927568&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    

    
      
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/papers/IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

    
  
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  
  &lt;p id=&quot;IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008-abstract&quot; class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;Ray chaos, manifested by the exponential divergence of trajectories originating from an originally thin ray bundle, can occur even in linear electromagnetic propagation environments, due to the inherent nonlinearity of ray-tracing (eikonal) maps. In this paper, extending our previous study of a two-dimensional planar ray-chaotic prototype scenario, we consider a cylindrical scatterer made of a perfectly electric-conducting azimuthally corrugated boundary coated by a radially inhomogeneous (ray-trapping) dielectric layer. For this configuration, we carry out a comprehensive parametric study of the ray-dynamical and full-wave scattering (monostatic and bistatic radar-cross-section) signatures, with emphasis on possible implications for high-frequency wave asymptotics (“ray-chaotic footprints”).&lt;/p&gt;
  

  &lt;pre id=&quot;IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008-bibtex&quot; class=&quot;pre pre-scrollable collapse&quot;&gt;@article{IJ57_IEEE_TAP_56_2638_2008,
  author = {Castaldi, G. and Galdi, V. and Pinto, I. M.},
  journal = {IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation},
  title = {A study of ray-chaotic cylindrical scatterers},
  year = {2008},
  volume = {56},
  number = {8},
  pages = {2638--2648},
  keywords = {electromagnetic wave propagation;electromagnetic wave scattering;ray tracing;dielectric layer;electric-conducting azimuthally corrugated boundary;full-wave scattering;high-frequency wave asymptotics;linear electromagnetic propagation environments;ray-chaotic cylindrical scatterers;ray-tracing maps;two-dimensional planar ray-chaotic prototype scenario;Chaos;Dielectrics;Electromagnetic propagation;Electromagnetic scattering;Hafnium;Particle scattering;Radar cross section;Radar scattering;Ray tracing;Trajectory;High-frequency;radar cross-section;ray chaos},
  doi = {10.1109/TAP.2008.927568},
  issn = {0018-926X},
  month = aug
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

  
    
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Vincenzo Galdi</name><email>vgaldi@unisannio.it</email></author><category term="ray chaos" /><category term="high-frequency" /><category term="scattering" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>
